- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh...
- ♪ 哦...
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
SpongeBob
SquarePants!
海绵宝宝
方裤！
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[playful music]
[俏皮的音乐]
♪
[bubbling]
[thump]
[冒泡]
[扑通]
[tense music]
[overlapping chatter]
[紧张的音乐]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
- Mr. Squidward.
- 章鱼哥先生。
What is happening
in me restaurant?
正在发生什么
在我的餐厅？
- The customers
have gone crazy.
- 客户
已经疯了。
- Ah!
- 啊！
- SpongeBob is late for work,
so there's no food.
- 海绵宝宝上班迟到了
所以没有食物。
- [gasps] But he's never been
late for work in his life.
- [喘气] 但他从来没有
他一生中上班迟到。
Oh, this can only mean
one thing.
哦，这只能说明
一件事。
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
SpongeBob has passed away.
海绵宝宝去世了。
all: [gasps]
全体：[喘气]
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
[solemn music]
[庄严的音乐]
♪
- Or... maybe he's just
seriously injured.
- 或者...也许他只是
重伤。
[chuckles]
[笑声]
all: [sobbing]
- Oh, yeah,
全体：[抽泣]
- 哦，是的，
that's still bad, isn't it?
那还是很糟糕，不是吗？
[sobs]
[抽泣]
- I had no idea you cared
that much about SpongeBob.
- 我不知道你在乎
关于海绵宝宝就这么多了。
- Of course.
- 当然。
He's been a loyal employee.
他一直是一名忠诚的员工。
His passing would be a great
loss to me bank account.
他的去世将是一个伟大的
我的银行账户遭受损失。
Oh, I--to me personally,
of course.
哦，我——就我个人而言，
当然。
Now, come on,
现在，来吧，
we have to go check on
SpongeBob's possible remains.
我们得去检查一下
海绵宝宝可能仍然存在。
- With pleasure.
- 荣幸。
- [groans]
- What? Too soon?
- [呻吟]
- 什么？太快了？
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[solemn music]
[庄严的音乐]
- Prepare yourselves
for the horror.
- 做好准备
为了恐怖。
Or the joy.
或者说是喜悦。
Let's not be downers
about this.
我们不要成为沮丧的人
关于这个。
- Oh, yeah.
- Okay.
- 哦，是的。
- 好的。
- But probably, like I said,
- 但也许，就像我说的，
the horror.
恐怖。
all: [gasp]
全体：[喘气]
[door creaks open]
[门嘎吱一声打开]
[whispering chatter]
[窃窃私语]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- Neptune's nightmare.
- 海王星的噩梦。
That snail is eating
SpongeBob's face.
那只蜗牛正在吃东西
海绵宝宝的脸。
Get away from him.
离他远点。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[overlapping chatter]
- Such a nice kid.
[重叠的喋喋不休]
- 真是个好孩子。
- I--I...
[babbles]
- 我--我...
[胡言乱语]
Oh, good morning, everyone.
哦，大家早上好。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[disappointed chatter]
[失望的喋喋不休]
- SpongeBob, you're alive!
- 海绵宝宝，你还活着！
- I am?
Well, thank goodness.
- 我是？
好吧，谢天谢地。
Wait, why wouldn't I be alive?
等等，我为什么不能活着？
- You were late to work,
so we assumed the worst.
- 你上班迟到了，
所以我们做了最坏的打算。
- You mean "the best."
- 你的意思是“最好的”。
- Late to work?
But that's impossible.
- 上班迟到？
但这是不可能的。
My trusty alarm clock
always waked me up.
我值得信赖的闹钟
总是叫醒我。
See?
Ah.
看？
啊。
Well, how do you like that?
It's unplugged.
嗯，你觉得怎么样？
它已拔掉插头。
Well, we'll just fix that
and I'll never be late again.
好吧，我们会解决这个问题
我再也不会迟到了。
Oh.
[grunts]
哦。
[咕哝]
[playful music]
[俏皮的音乐]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Ah.
啊。
- Oh, my clock!
- 哦，我的时钟！
- Huh? Ah.
- Mm?
- 啊？啊。
- 毫米？
Looks like you need
a new clock, boyo.
看起来你需要
一个新时钟，博约。
- Oh, I could never replace
my old clock, Mr. Krabs.
- 哦，我永远无法取代
我的老钟，蟹老板。
We've been through
too much together.
我们已经经历过
在一起太多了。
It's the only alarm clock
I've ever owned.
这是唯一的闹钟
我曾经拥有过。
I can fix it.
我可以修好它。
- Eh, good luck.
- 呃，祝你好运。
But you better
not be late tomorrow.
但你最好
明天不迟到。
Or else.
否则。
- Did that stupid clock
give me a bump on my head?
- 那个愚蠢的时钟吗？
给我撞一下我的头吗？
- [scream]
both: Ugh.
- [尖叫]
两人：呃。
- [snoring]
- Oh, come on, come on.
- [打鼾]
-哦，来吧，来吧。
I still love you.
Let me fix you.
我依然爱你。
让我来修复你。
Wow!
哇！
- [grunts, gulps, exhales]
- [咕哝，吞咽，呼气]
Ooh, hey, SpongeBob,
what're you doing?
哦，嘿，海绵宝宝，
你在做什么？
- Mm.
- 毫米。
Oh, I'm just trying to fix
this old alarm clock.
哦，我只是想修复
这个旧闹钟。
I'm gonna need that part you
swallowed, by the way.
我需要你的那部分
顺便说一下，被吞掉了。
- That's cool.
- 这很酷。
Just give me a couple of hours.
给我几个小时。
You know, I could totally fix
your clock for you.
你知道，我完全可以解决
你的时钟。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Oh, I don't know, Patrick.
- 哦，我不知道，帕特里克。
This clock means a lot to me
and...
这个时钟对我来说意义重大
还有……
- [eager giggle]
- [急切的咯咯笑]
- Well, okay, are you sure?
- 好吧，你确定吗？
- Absolutely.
Don't you worry.
- 绝对地。
别担心。
I promise to be super careful.
我保证会超级小心。
[grunting, groaning]
[咕哝，呻吟]
- Ah!
- 啊！
- Why don't you fix?
- 你为什么不修好？
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
Hmm?
Uh...
唔？
呃...
Sorry, SpongeBob,
I couldn't fix it.
对不起，海绵宝宝，
我无法修复它。
- Thanks for trying, Patrick,
- 谢谢你的尝试，帕特里克，
but I guess nothing
lasts forever.
但我猜没什么
永远持续下去。
Looks like I'm gonna need
a new clock after all.
看来我需要
毕竟是一个新时钟。
- Hmm!
[laughs]
- 唔！
[笑]
In that case...
在这种情况下...
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[lively music]
[活泼的音乐]
- Um, hello?
- 嗯，你好？
- Hello, there.
- 你好呀。
Welcome to Clock World,
where we always have time
欢迎来到时钟世界，
我们总是有时间的地方
for a bargain.
为了讨价还价。
How can I help you?
我怎么帮你？
- Do you have another alarm
clock like my old one?
- 你还有另一个闹钟吗
时钟像我的旧时钟一样吗？
[plops]
[扑通扑通]
- Hmm?
- 唔？
[tongue slurps,
palatal click]
[舌头发出声音，
腭音]
Ah, the 740 Foghorn
Wake-Em-Up Grand.
啊，740 雾号
唤醒他们盛大。
I'm sorry to say they don't
make this model anymore.
很遗憾他们没有
不再做这个模型了。
But if you have a second,
但如果你还有时间的话
I have many others
I can show you. [giggles]
我还有很多其他的
我可以给你看。 [咯咯笑]
- Wow. So many to choose from.
- 哇。有这么多可供选择。
Oh, I'll never be able
to choose a clock
哦，我永远无法
选择时钟
with this many choices.
有这么多选择。
- I'll just take 'em all.
- 我会把它们全部拿走。
- Ah!, I'm rich.
- 啊！，我很有钱。
[maniacal laughter]
Whoo!
[疯狂的笑声]
呼！
Whoo, whoo, whoo, whoo!
呼、呼、呼、呼！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪
- [meows]
- [喵]
- My old foghorn clock was
the only alarm clock
- 我的旧雾号钟是
唯一的闹钟
that could wake me up.
这可以叫醒我。
Sure hope one of these works.
当然希望这些作品之一。
Goodnight, Gare-bear.
晚安，车站熊。
[gargle snoring]
[漱口打鼾]
[tranquil music]
[安静的音乐]
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
[gargles]
[漱口]
[snores]
[打鼾]
male narrator:
One hour later...
男旁白：
一小时后...
[rooster crows]
- Huh?
[公鸡打鸣]
- 啊？
[babbling]
[胡说]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Late.
- 晚的。
- I hope this one works.
- 我希望这个能起作用。
[squeals]
[尖叫声]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[dramatic music]
[bell rings]
[戏剧音乐]
[铃声响起]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
narrator: Late again...
旁白：又迟到了……
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
- Late.
- 晚的。
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
♪
Huh?
啊？
[jellyfish buzz]
[水母嗡嗡声]
narrator: You get the idea.
旁白：你明白了。
- Late.
- 晚的。
Late.
晚的。
Still late.
Late.
还是迟到了。
晚的。
Late, late, late, late, late,
late, late.
迟到，迟到，迟到，迟到，迟到，
迟到了，迟到了。
- Still late.
- [whimpers]
- 还是迟到了。
- [呜咽]
- Late again.
- 又迟到了。
I told you before
that you best not be late
我之前告诉过你
你最好不要迟到
or else.
或者其他。
But this time,
I'll be emphasizing it
但这一次，
我会强调一下
with a furrowed brow.
皱着眉头。
Or else.
否则。
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
- Oh, I don't know how many
more "or elses" I can take.
- 哦，我不知道有多少
我可以接受更多的“否则”。
I have to figure out a way
to wake up on time.
我得想个办法
准时起床。
[alarm rings]
[警报响起]
- [meows excitedly]
- [兴奋地喵喵叫]
[lively music]
[bell rings]
[活泼的音乐]
[铃声响起]
♪
- Hey, what a great idea.
- 嘿，真是个好主意。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
♪
Oh.
[moans]
哦。
[呻吟声]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[alarm blaring]
[警报声]
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
[playful music]
[俏皮的音乐]
[thump]
[扑通]
[buzz]
[嗡嗡声]
[spring boings]
[春天的轰鸣声]
♪
[snoring]
[打鼾]
- Hmm, I really thought that
last "or else" would've worked.
- 嗯，我真的这么认为
最后一个“否则”就可以了。
Maybe I should've
wagged my finger.
也许我应该
摇动我的手指。
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
♪
- Ah!
- Right on time.
- 啊！
- 准时。
Looks like I won't be needing
you after all, SpongeTom.
看来我不需要
毕竟是你，海绵汤姆。
- Oh.
- 哦。
♪
- Good morning.
[grunts]
- 早上好。
[咕哝]
[sizzling]
[嘶嘶声]
[clock cuckoos]
[钟杜鹃]
- [meows, groans]
- [喵喵声，呻吟声]
♪
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
♪
- Sadly, it looks like your
order's on time today.
- 可悲的是，它看起来像你的
今天订单准时。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
[bell rings]
D'oh!
[铃声响起]
噢！
- [gleeful groans]
- [高兴的呻吟声]
Glad you finally
woke up on time, boyo.
很高兴你终于
准时起床，博约。
[laughs]
[笑]
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
- Just five more minutes,
Gary.
- 再过五分钟，
加里.
both: [grunt]
两者：[咕哝]
- Sir, there's a line.
- 先生，有一条线。
- I'm filing a complaint.
- 我正在提出投诉。
I ordered this
with extra pickles.
我订购了这个
加上额外的泡菜。
And I only count fourteen.
而我只数到了十四。
- SpongeBob,
we got a wrong order.
- 海绵宝宝，
我们接到了错误的订单。
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[playful suspenseful music]
【俏皮悬疑的音乐】
[sizzling]
[嘶嘶声]
♪
[clock cuckoos]
[钟杜鹃]
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
♪
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- What in Poseidon's beard?
- 波塞冬的胡子里有什么？
- [gasps]
Oh. Oh.
- [喘气]
哦。哦。
Good morning, Mr. Krabs.
早上好，蟹老板。
- It's not a good morning.
- 这不是一个美好的早晨。
First, you're late for days,
首先，你迟到了几天，
and now you destroyed
me kitchen.
现在你毁了
我的厨房。
- [laughs nervously]
- [紧张地笑]
- Oh, looks like it's--
- 哦，看起来是——
- Time for "or else?"
- 是时候说“否则？”
[dramatic music]
- You better be at work on time
[戏剧音乐]
- 你最好准时上班
or else I'll have to open up
不然我就得敞开心扉
and close the restaurant
an hour later.
并关闭餐厅
一个小时后。
- Uh, what?
- 呃，什么？
No!
不！
[door slams open]
- [grunts]
[门砰地一声打开]
- [咕哝]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
I did it.
我做到了。
- [gasps]
Yes!
- [喘气]
是的！
Oh, Patrick, you fixed it.
哦，帕特里克，你修好了。
- Uh, kind of.
- 呃，有点。
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[foghorn blares]
[雾号声]
[laughter]
[笑声]
[tranquil music]
[安静的音乐]
♪